<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tech | Will Thames]]></title>
  <link href="http://thames.localhost/articles/categories/tech/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thames.localhost/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-18T20:49:07+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://thames.localhost/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Will Thames]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech behind the blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://thames.localhost/article/2012/09/18/tech-behind-the-blog/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T18:57:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://thames.localhost/article/2012/09/18/tech-behind-the-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've moved the blog from <a href="http://willthames.org.uk">willthames.org.uk</a>
to reflect my new location and just for an opportunity for a refresh.</p>

<p>I was relatively happy with <a href="http://drupal.org">Drupal</a>'s flexibility
but just didn't need that much
power. Also, something a lot simpler means that I can customise it that much
more easily.</p>

<p>In the end I went with <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> using the
<a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/blog-migrations">Drupal migration</a>
for <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a>.
Currently it's only migrated my posts - not my race
reports or training log. I'll worry about that later. Using octopress allows
me to store my blog posts in git and then upload them to
<a href="http://heroku.com/">Heroku</a> - so free blog posting in quite a simple fashion.
The only thing I don't like about the
combination is that I have to keep the generated pages under version control,
but the opportunity to use and learn a bit more about Heroku was more
compelling than just using github pages.</p>

<p>For theming, I really wanted to keep the left hand bar, and I just couldn't
easily work out how to do it using octopress's default theme. The
<a href="https://github.com/barmstrong/octopress-bootstrap">bootstrap theme</a> for
octopress was a lot easier to customise, mostly because
<a href="http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap">Bootstrap</a> is so simple to use.
I've made a few of my own tweaks
(most of which I've submitted as a pull request) and some simple CSS
customisations on top.</p>

<p>I've also changed the tag line from "swim, bike, run", to add the word tech.
I imagine my blog will remain more about running than anything else, but
there will definitely be the odd technical post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
