<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tech | Will Thames]]></title>
  <link href="http://thames.localhost/articles/categories/tech/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://thames.localhost/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-30T21:39:54+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://thames.localhost/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Will Thames]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[training log data]]></title>
    <link href="http://thames.localhost/article/2012/10/30/training-log-data/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-30T21:18:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://thames.localhost/article/2012/10/30/training-log-data</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Training Log Data</h1>

<p>I've really wanted to be able to take more control of my data for years.
In recent months this has become more concrete and I've focussed all the
time I have to dedicate to coding to just working on the visualisation of
my training data.</p>

<p>I've strived to favour shipping over perfection - various choices that I've
made have been short-term so that I can get <em>something</em> out there. At
present I have to manually run a script that takes binary formatted data from
my watch and turns it into JSON. <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>
can do the rest, with the help of a plugin I wrote to generate the three
types of 'pages' that power the training log: the training log entry itself,
the data behind that training log entry, and the index of all training logs.</p>

<p>I have made incredibly heavy use of other people's work. For dynamic
visualisation, <a href="https://github.com/mbostock/d3">d3</a> is pretty
much the best thing out there - it does all kinds of graphs, tables, maps and
much more. For mapping, I used <a href="http://leafletjs.com/">Leaflet</a>,
backed by the tiles of <a href="http://cloudmade.com">CloudMade</a>, which
rely on the data of <a href="http://openstreetmap.org">OpenStreetMap</a>.</p>

<p>To be honest, the results aren't much different to what I currently get from
<a href="http://connect.garmin.com">Garmin Connect</a>, but this is just the
first step.</p>

<p>There are bugs. If the training data doesn't show first time, just refresh.
I think that's a fairly normal Javascript script loading ordering problem,
that I haven't fixed over shipping (and writing this page). The time x-axis
is currently in seconds (I'd rather have 1:00 than 3600 but I haven't yet
worked that one out).</p>

<p>Other things on my list include publishing the script I use to convert
Garmin FIT data to JSON, based on the
<a href="https://github.com/dtcooper/python-fitparse">fitparse library</a>,
plotting lap markers, having lap popups. It's quite exciting, the
possibilities are endless. Oh, and the <a href="http://thames.localhost/training">training log</a>
index needs some styling applied. But at least it has some entries.</p>

<p>And there's</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech behind the blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://thames.localhost/article/2012/09/18/tech-behind-the-blog/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T18:57:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://thames.localhost/article/2012/09/18/tech-behind-the-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've moved the blog from <a href="http://willthames.org.uk">willthames.org.uk</a>
to reflect my new location and just for an opportunity for a refresh.</p>

<p>I was relatively happy with <a href="http://drupal.org">Drupal</a>'s flexibility
but just didn't need that much
power. Also, something a lot simpler means that I can customise it that much
more easily.</p>

<p>In the end I went with <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> using the
<a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/blog-migrations">Drupal migration</a>
for <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a>.
Currently it's only migrated my posts - not my race
reports or training log. I'll worry about that later. Using octopress allows
me to store my blog posts in git and then upload them to
<a href="http://heroku.com/">Heroku</a> - so free blog posting in quite a simple fashion.
The only thing I don't like about the
combination is that I have to keep the generated pages under version control,
but the opportunity to use and learn a bit more about Heroku was more
compelling than just using github pages.</p>

<p>For theming, I really wanted to keep the left hand bar, and I just couldn't
easily work out how to do it using octopress's default theme. The
<a href="https://github.com/barmstrong/octopress-bootstrap">bootstrap theme</a> for
octopress was a lot easier to customise, mostly because
<a href="http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap">Bootstrap</a> is so simple to use.
I've made a few of my own tweaks
(most of which I've submitted as a pull request) and some simple CSS
customisations on top.</p>

<p>I've also changed the tag line from "swim, bike, run", to add the word tech.
I imagine my blog will remain more about running than anything else, but
there will definitely be the odd technical post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
